Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Notebooks, 3
  - Blue notebook [no. 55], April 23-July 16, 1983; MacCreadyPB_03_00_008_11 (Box 3.8, Folder 11)
  - Blue notebook [no. 56], July 17-December 23, 1983; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_01 (Box 3.9, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 57], July 17-December 23, 1983; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_02 (Box 3.9, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 58], December 23, 1983-March 15, 1984; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_03 (Box 3.9, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 59], March 15-June 19, 1984; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_04 (Box 3.9, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 60], June 19-September 27, 1984; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_05 (Box 3.9, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 61], September 28-November 17, 1984; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_06 (Box 3.9, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 62], November 18, 1984-March 9, 1985; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_07 (Box 3.9, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 63], March 9-June 14, 1985; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_08 (Box 3.9, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 64], June 14-September 9, 1985; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_09 (Box 3.9, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 65], September 10-December 12, 1985; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_10 (Box 3.9, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 66], December 7, 1985-March 13, 1986; MacCreadyPB_03_00_009_11 (Box 3.9, Folder 11)
  - Blue notebook [no. 67], March 13-June 5, 1986; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_01 (Box 3.10, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 68], June 5-October 6, 1986; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_02 (Box 3.10, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 69], October 6, 1986-January 19, 1987; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_03 (Box 3.10, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 70], January 20-April 14, 1987; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_04 (Box 3.10, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 71], April 13-July 16, 1987; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_05 (Box 3.10, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 72], July 16-November 13, 1987; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_06 (Box 3.10, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 73], November 16, 1987-February 16, 1988; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_07 (Box 3.10, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 74], February 18-May 24, 1988; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_08 (Box 3.10, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 75], May 24-September 8, 1988; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_09 (Box 3.10, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 76], September 9, 1988-January 12, 1989; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_10 (Box 3.10, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 77], January 13-May 6, 1989; MacCreadyPB_03_00_010_11 (Box 3.10, Folder 11)
  - Blue notebook [no. 78], May 7-August 15, 1989; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_01 (Box 3.11, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 79], August 16-October 31, 1989; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_02 (Box 3.11, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 80], November 1, 1989-February 19, 1990; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_03 (Box 3.11, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 81], February 15-May 27, 1990; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_04 (Box 3.11, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 82], May 27-August 10, 1990; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_05 (Box 3.11, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 83], August 9-October 22, 1990; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_06 (Box 3.11, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 84], October 23, 1990-February 4, 1991; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_07 (Box 3.11, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 85], February 7-April 25, 1991; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_08 (Box 3.11, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 86], April 25-June 23, 1991; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_09 (Box 3.11, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 87], June 24-September 2, 1991; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_10 (Box 3.11, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 88], September 3-November 6, 1991; MacCreadyPB_03_00_011_11 (Box 3.11, Folder 11)
  - Blue notebook [no. 89], November 7, 1991-February 24, 1992; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_01 (Box 3.12, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 90], February 19-April 23, 1992; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_02 (Box 3.12, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 91], April 23-August 19, 1992; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_03 (Box 3.12, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 92], August 1-December 31, 1992; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_04 (Box 3.12, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 93], January 1-April 12, 1993; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_05 (Box 3.12, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 94], April 12-July 19, 1993; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_06 (Box 3.12, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 97], January 31-May 10, 1994; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_07 (Box 3.12, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 98], May 13-August 13, 1994; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_08 (Box 3.12, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 99], August 22-November 1, 1994; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_09 (Box 3.12, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 100], November 1, 1994-February 1, 1995; MacCreadyPB_03_00_012_10 (Box 3.12, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 102], February 20-May 11, 1995; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_01 (Box 3.13, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 103], March 21-August 13, 1995; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_02 (Box 3.13, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 104], August 14-November 14, 1995; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_03 (Box 3.13, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 105], November 14, 1995-February 29, 1996; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_04 (Box 3.13, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 106], March 1-June 22, 1996; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_05 (Box 3.13, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 107], May 20-August 23, 1996; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_06 (Box 3.13, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 108], August 25-December 12, 1996; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_07 (Box 3.13, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 109], December 13, 1996-March, 19, 1997; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_08 (Box 3.13, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 110], March 20-April 25, 1997; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_09 (Box 3.13, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 111], April 28-July 31, 1997; MacCreadyPB_03_00_013_10 (Box 3.13, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 112], August 1-November 18, 1997; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_01 (Box 3.14, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 113], November 18, 1997-January 1, 1998; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_02 (Box 3.14, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 114], January 2-March 19, 1998; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_03 (Box 3.14, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 115], March 20-June 11, 1998; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_04 (Box 3.14, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 116], June 11-September 8, 1998; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_05 (Box 3.14, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 117], September 8-December 4, 1998; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_06 (Box 3.14, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 118], December 5, 1998-April 20, 1999; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_07 (Box 3.14, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 119], April 21-September 8, 1999; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_08 (Box 3.14, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 120], September 9-December 13, 1999; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_09 (Box 3.14, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 121], January 1-April 15, 2000; MacCreadyPB_03_00_014_10 (Box 3.14, Folder 10)
  - Blue notebook [no. 122], April 15-July 19, 2000; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_01 (Box 3.15, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook [no. 123], July 19-November 8, 2000; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_02 (Box 3.15, Folder 2)
  - Blue notebook [no. 124], November 10, 2000-February 2, 2001; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_03 (Box 3.15, Folder 3)
  - Blue notebook [no. 125], February 4-May 30, 2001; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_04 (Box 3.15, Folder 4)
  - Blue notebook [no. 126], May 29-September 11, 2001; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_05 (Box 3.15, Folder 5)
  - Blue notebook [no. 127], September 12-December 31, 2001; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_06 (Box 3.15, Folder 6)
  - Blue notebook [no. 128], January 1-March 18, 2002; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_07 (Box 3.15, Folder 7)
  - Blue notebook [no. 129], March 19-May 29, 2002; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_08 (Box 3.15, Folder 8)
  - Blue notebook [no. 130], May 29-September 10, 2002; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_09 (Box 3.15, Folder 9)
  - Blue notebook [no. 131], September 11-December 30, 2002; MacCreadyPB_03_00_015_10 (Box 3.15, Folder 10)
- Writings and talks, 4
  - Writings, 1
    - Gas model airfoils: A modeler's reply to the engineer, undated; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_01 (Box 4.1, Folder 1)
    - Freaks, Air Trails Pictorial, 1945 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_02 (Box 4.1, Folder 2)
    - Uncle Sam's third international glider record since the Wright Brothers, Soaring, 1948 January-February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_03 (Box 4.1, Folder 3)
    - A new altitude record - the lowest sailplane flight ever made, and Thunderstorm Soaring, 1949 April; June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_04 (Box 4.1, Folder 4)
    - West to Ohio, Soaring, 1949 July-August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_05 (Box 4.1, Folder 5)
    - The Schweizer 1-23 Sailplane, Flying, 1950 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_06 (Box 4.1, Folder 6)
    - Upcurrents for your model, Air Trails Pictorial Vol. XXXIV, No. 2, 1950 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_07 (Box 4.1, Folder 7)
    - Cloud seeding over the Salt, Tonto and Verde River waterheads, 1950-1951 Winter; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_08 (Box 4.1, Folder 8)
    - Cloud seeding: a new technology, Engineering and Science Monthly, 1951 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_09 (Box 4.1, Folder 9)
    - Is cloud seeding worthwhile? Arizona Stockman, 1951 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_10 (Box 4.1, Folder 10)
    - Results of cloud seeding in Central Arizona, Winter 1951, Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society Vol. 33, No. 2, 1952 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_11 (Box 4.1, Folder 11)
    - Atmospheric turbulence measurements and analysis. United States Weather Bureau, 1952 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_12 (Box 4.1, Folder 12)
    - Investigation of atmospheric turbulence and aircraft response characteristics by means of gliders, 1952-1954; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_13 (Box 4.1, Folder 13)
    - Structure of atmospheric turbulence, Journal of Meteorology Vol. 10, No. 6, 1953 December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_14 (Box 4.1, Folder 14)
    - Project Skyfire-A progress report on lightning fire and atmospheric research. United States Department of Agriculture Forest Service, 1954 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_15 (Box 4.1, Folder 15)
    - High and low elevations as thermal source regions, Weather Vol. X, No. 2, 1955 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_16 (Box 4.1, Folder 16)
    - Project Skyfire-- Cloud and lightning observation handbook. United States Department of Agriculture Forest Service, 1955 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_17 (Box 4.1, Folder 17)
    - Atmospheric turbulence investigation by Sailplane, Final Report, 1956 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_18 (Box 4.1, Folder 18)
    - Joint SSA-AMS meeting, Soaring, 1956 July-August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_19 (Box 4.1, Folder 19)
    - Flying in the 1956 Internationals, Soaring Vol. 20, No. 6, 1956 November-December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_20 (Box 4.1, Folder 20)
    - Physical evaluation of cloud seeding effects, 1956 December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_21 (Box 4.1, Folder 21)
    - Hills are thermal producers, AND More comparisons (written by Paul MacCready, Sr.) Soaring Vol. 21, No. 1, 1957 January-February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_22 (Box 4.1, Folder 22)
    - Let's break some records, Soaring, 1957 March-April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_23 (Box 4.1, Folder 23)
    - Silent adventure, Flying Vol. 60, No. 6, 1957 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_24 (Box 4.1, Folder 24)
    - Final report of the Advisory Committee on Weather Control, Vol. I, 1957 December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_25 (Box 4.1, Folder 25)
    - Final report of the Advisory Committee on Weather Control, Vol. II, 1957 December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_001_26 (Box 4.1, Folder 26)
    - Cloud electrification study. Final report prepared for the Atomic Energy Commission, 1958 September; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_01 (Box 4.2, Folder 1)
    - Discriminations between condensation-coalescence and ice crystal produced precipitation, Seventh Weather Radar Conference Proceedings, 1958 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_02 (Box 4.2, Folder 2)
    - The lightning mechanism and its relation to natural and artificial freezing nuclei, Recent advances in atmospheric electricity, 1959; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_03 (Box 4.2, Folder 3)
    - Cloud electrification study. Final report prepared for the Atomic Energy Commission, 1959 July; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_04 (Box 4.2, Folder 4)
    - Flagstaff cloud physics studies service project, 1959 December 10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_05 (Box 4.2, Folder 5)
    - Santa Barbara Weather Modification Project. State of California Department of Water Resources, 1960 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_06 (Box 4.2, Folder 6)
    - Improving thermal soaring flight techniques, 1961; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_07 (Box 4.2, Folder 7)
    - A Review of small cumulus studies and the modification of hail, Nubila Anno IV, N. 1, 1961; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_08 (Box 4.2, Folder 8)
    - Final report of the 1961 Yellowstone Field Research Seminar, MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_09 (Box 4.2, Folder 9)
    - The continuous particle sampler at the Puy de Dome comparison conference, Bulletin de L'Observatoire du Puy de Dome No. 1, 1962; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_10 (Box 4.2, Folder 10)
    - The minimum glider, The Thermal, 1963 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_11 (Box 4.2, Folder 11)
    - Study and modification of convective storms, 1963 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_12 (Box 4.2, Folder 12)
    - Hydrometeor charge evolution in thunderstorms, 1963 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_13 (Box 4.2, Folder 13)
    - Finding thermals by radar, The Thermal, 1963 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_14 (Box 4.2, Folder 14)
    - Continuous particle sampler study program, 1963 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_15 (Box 4.2, Folder 15)
    - Flagstaff cumulus studies, 1964 Spring; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_16 (Box 4.2, Folder 16)
    - Continuous particle sampler, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 3, No. 4, 1964 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_17 (Box 4.2, Folder 17)
    - Standardization of gustiness values from aircraft, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 3, No. 4, 1964 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_18 (Box 4.2, Folder 18)
    - Observations of hydrometeor charge evolution in thunderstorms, Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society Vol. 91, No. 387, 1965 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_19 (Box 4.2, Folder 19)
    - Self-charging of melting ice, Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society Vol. 91, No. 387, 1965 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_20 (Box 4.2, Folder 20)
    - The 1965 Flagstaff cloud seeding program, 1965 September 3; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_21 (Box 4.2, Folder 21)
    - The Flagstaff cumulus studies and cloud modification program, 1965 September 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_002_22 (Box 4.2, Folder 22)
    - Analysis of Flagstaff data, 1966 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_01 (Box 4.3, Folder 1)
    - Aerosol difusion over shoreline complexes, 1966 May 2; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_02 (Box 4.3, Folder 2)
    - Hailswath program analysis and hail suppression program planning, 1966 October 21; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_03 (Box 4.3, Folder 3)
    - Cloud buoyancy increase due to seeding, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 6, No. 1, 1967 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_04 (Box 4.3, Folder 4)
    - Atmospheric diffusion in the inertial subrange, 1967 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_05 (Box 4.3, Folder 5)
    - Aircraft probing of natural and seeded clouds for Project Skyfire, 1967 April 15; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_06 (Box 4.3, Folder 6)
    - Arizona weather modification research program, 1967 April 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_07 (Box 4.3, Folder 7)
    - Designing programs involving convective clouds, 1967 October 12-13; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_08 (Box 4.3, Folder 8)
    - Aircraft observations in Alberta, 1967 December 29; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_09 (Box 4.3, Folder 9)
    - Cloud physics observations in South Dakota cumulus clouds, 1967 December 31; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_10 (Box 4.3, Folder 10)
    - The glaciation of an AgI-seeded cumulus clouds, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 7, No. 1, 1968 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_11 (Box 4.3, Folder 11)
    - Aircraft probing of hailstorms, 1968 March 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_12 (Box 4.3, Folder 12)
    - Arizona weather modification research program 1 of 2, 1968 June 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_13 (Box 4.3, Folder 13)
    - Arizona weather modification research program 2 of 2, 1968 June 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_003_14 (Box 4.3, Folder 14)
    - Analysis of warm cloud modification potential, 1968 June 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_01 (Box 4.4, Folder 1)
    - Precipitation initiation mechanisms and droplet characteristics of some convective cloud cores, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 7, No. 4, 1968 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_02 (Box 4.4, Folder 2)
    - Study of the engineering of cloud seeding, 1968 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_03 (Box 4.4, Folder 3)
    - The Arizona weather modification research program and associated studies, 1968 August 31; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_04 (Box 4.4, Folder 4)
    - Warm fog modification, 1969 January 20; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_05 (Box 4.4, Folder 5)
    - An isolated cumulus cloud modification project, Journal of Applied Meteorology Vol. 8, No. 6, 1969 December; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_06 (Box 4.4, Folder 6)
    - An assesment of dominant mechanisms in vortex-wake decay, Aircraft wake turbulence, 1970; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_07 (Box 4.4, Folder 7)
    - Escadrille Aircraft Corporation: A planfor development, 1970 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_08 (Box 4.4, Folder 8)
    - Cloud electrification at Flagstaff, 1969, 1970 January 29; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_09 (Box 4.4, Folder 9)
    - Turbulence and hail suppression, 1970 January 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_10 (Box 4.4, Folder 10)
    - Arizona weather modification research program, Journal of the Irrigation and Drainage Division, 1970 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_11 (Box 4.4, Folder 11)
    - The electrification of seeded and unseeded clouds, 1970 August 24-26; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_12 (Box 4.4, Folder 12)
    - Within-cloud measurements on thunderstorm electrification, 1970 September 18; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_13 (Box 4.4, Folder 13)
    - Assessment of the effect of aircraft on clouds, 1971 March 10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_14 (Box 4.4, Folder 14)
    - Hygroscopic seeding in Oklahoma, 1971 October 31; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_15 (Box 4.4, Folder 15)
    - Instrumentation for soaring, 1972; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_16 (Box 4.4, Folder 16)
    - Appraisal of present and projected state of the art (1985) in weather modification, 1972 January 31; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_17 (Box 4.4, Folder 17)
    - The Peebles computer, Aero-Revue, 1972 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_18 (Box 4.4, Folder 18)
    - Dissipation of convective clouds by aircraft, 1972 May 26; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_19 (Box 4.4, Folder 19)
    - Aircraft vortex-wake effects on particle transport, breakup, and coalesence, 1973 January 2; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_20 (Box 4.4, Folder 20)
    - Development of devices to reduce aerodynamic drag of large highway trucks, 1974 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_21 (Box 4.4, Folder 21)
    - Diffusion and turbulence aloft over complex terrain, Symposium on atmospheric diffusion and air pollution, American Meteorological Society, 1974 September 9 - 13; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_22 (Box 4.4, Folder 22)
    - Investigation of the motion and decay of the vortex wake of a light twin-engine aircraft, 1974 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_23 (Box 4.4, Folder 23)
    - A report on: the Second International Symposium on the technology & science of low-speed & motorless flight, Soaring Vol. 38, No. 12, 1974 December 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_24 (Box 4.4, Folder 24)
    - The estimation of turbulence by an aircraft pilot, 1974 December 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_004_25 (Box 4.4, Folder 25)
    - Turbulence and the local flow field. The AV experiment on DaVinci I, 1975 September 15; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_01 (Box 4.5, Folder 1)
    - Hang glider performance: comparisons, fundamentals, and potentials, Ground Skimmer, 1976 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_02 (Box 4.5, Folder 2)
    - Best flight speeds to the next thermal, and Warning - turbulence ahead, Ground Skimmer, 1976 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_03 (Box 4.5, Folder 3)
    - Developments in ultralight gliding, Soaring, 1976 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_04 (Box 4.5, Folder 4)
    - Soaring bird aerodynamics - clues for hang gliding, Ground Skimmer, 1976 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_05 (Box 4.5, Folder 5)
    - Assessment of atmospheric effects on the behavior of aircraft vortices, 1977 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_06 (Box 4.5, Folder 6)
    - Suggested rules for human-powered flight records, 1977 May 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_07 (Box 4.5, Folder 7)
    - Turbulence investigation on DaVinci II, 1977 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_08 (Box 4.5, Folder 8)
    - The Gossamer Condor, Human Power Vol. 1, No. 1, Winter 1977-1978; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_09 (Box 4.5, Folder 9)
    - Flight of the Gossamer Condor, Science Year, The World Book Science Annual, 1977-1979; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_10 (Box 4.5, Folder 10)
    - Manpowered flight - now what? Soaring Vol. 42, No. 1, 1978 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_11 (Box 4.5, Folder 11)
    - Flight on 0.33 horsepower: The Gossamer Condor, AIAA 14th annual meeting and technical display, 1978 February 7-9; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_12 (Box 4.5, Folder 12)
    - A case study in design, the Gossamer Condor, Astronautics & Aeronautics, 1978-1979; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_13 (Box 4.5, Folder 13)
    - Stability and control at speeds of under 5m/sec, Man powered flight, the channel crossing and the future, Third man powered aircraft group symposium, 1979 February 6; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_14 (Box 4.5, Folder 14)
    - Crossing the Channel in the Gossamer Albatross, The Society of Experimental Test Pilots 23rd symposium, Technical Review Vol. 14, No. 4, 1979 September 26-29; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_15 (Box 4.5, Folder 15)
    - On Gossamer wings, WPI Journal Vol. 84, No. 1, 1980 Summer; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_16 (Box 4.5, Folder 16)
    - The human motor: ordinary people doing extraordinary things, The Energy Consumer, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_04_01_005_17 (Box 4.5, Folder 17)
    - Piloted solar powered flight, 1981 February 4; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_01 (Box 4.6, Folder 1)
    - Sun powered aircraft design, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics annual meeting "Frontiers of achievement", 1981 May 12-14; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_02 (Box 4.6, Folder 2)
    - Human powered flight; Panel discussion: The future practical machine; Panel discussion: HPV's as a popular alternative, The first human powered vehicle scientific symposium proceedings, 1981 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_03 (Box 4.6, Folder 3)
    - Understanding speed-to-fly and the speed ring, Soaring, 1982 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_04 (Box 4.6, Folder 4)
    - A conversation with Paul B. MacCready, Jr: Unorthodox approach needed to solve today's problems, U.S. News & World report, 1982 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_05 (Box 4.6, Folder 5)
    - The Gossamer Condor; Structural developments from Kitty Hawk to the Gossamer Condor Guggenheim Aeronautical Laboratory at the California Institute of Technology - the first fifty years, 1983; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_06 (Box 4.6, Folder 6)
    - Trailblazers, Science Digest, 1983 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_07 (Box 4.6, Folder 7)
    - Human Nature: the floating needle, Science Digest, 1983 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_08 (Box 4.6, Folder 8)
    - Gossamer genesis, Ultralight Pilot Vol. 2, No. 2, 1983 March-April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_09 (Box 4.6, Folder 9)
    - Flirting with flight, YSM interview with Paul MacCready Yale Scientific Vol. 57, No. 4, 1983 Summer; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_10 (Box 4.6, Folder 10)
    - Sun powered aircraft designs, Journal of Aircraft Vol. 20, No. 6, 1983 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_11 (Box 4.6, Folder 11)
    - An interview with Paul MacCready, Free Inquiry Vol. 3, No. 4, 1983 Fall; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_12 (Box 4.6, Folder 12)
    - Human powered flight; Practical vehicles [2 articles], Second international human powered vehicle scientific symposium proceedings, 1983 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_13 (Box 4.6, Folder 13)
    - Successful flying toys, Free Flight, Ca. 1984; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_14 (Box 4.6, Folder 14)